Guide to the Raisa Berg Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VI: Research and Reference Materials, 1919-2004
  - Subseries VI.1: Writings by Others, 1919-2003
    - Various authors:
      - Miroshnichenko, E.Ia.: see Ginzburg, E.KH.
      - Miyake, T.: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Mizobuchi, K.: see Demerec, Milislav.
      - Mizrokhi, Lev J.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Moav, Rom, 1958 (Box 66, Folder 16)
      - Model, Peter: see Chung Nan Chang
      - Moiseev, N.N., 1981 (Box 66, Folder 16)
      - Monje, C.A.: see Hoenigsberg, H.F.
      - Mookerjee, Sivatosh, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 16)
      - Moriwaki, Daigoro, undated (Box 66, Folder 16)
      - Morrill, Thomas A., undated (Box 66, Folder 16)
      - Morrison, Russell J.: see Lim, J.K.
      - Mosolov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich, 1968-1981 (with author's inscription) (Box 66, Folder 17)
      - Mravlag, Heide Feuerbach: see Sperlich, Diether
      - Muller, Andreas, 1961 (with author's inscription) (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Muller, Dagmar, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Muller, H.J., 1939-1951 (including materials about him) (Box 67, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Muller, Rolf: see Muller, Dagmar
      - Muller-Hill, Benno, 1987 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - Muntzing, Arne, 1954-1973 (Box 67, Folder 5)
      - Muretov, G.D., 1939 (with author's inscription) (Box 67, Folder 6)
      - Murav'ev, A.: see Elens, Antoine
      - Myers, C.M.: see Iltis, W.G.
      - Nadler, Ch.F.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Nag, D.K.: see Berg, Douglas E.
      - Narain, Prem: see Nei, Masatoshi
      - Needham, Joseph, undated (Box 67, Folder 7)
      - Neel, James V., 1942 (Box 67, Folder 7)
      - Nei, Masatoshi, 1981-1982 (see also Kidwell; Maruyama, Takeo) (Box 67, Folder 7)
      - Neifakh, A.A., 1982 (Box 67, Folder 8)
      - Neiding, V.L., 1977-1979 (with author's inscription) (Box 67, Folder 8)
      - Nekrasov, A.D., 1933 (Box 67, Folder 8)
      - Nelson-Rees, Walter A., 1959-1962 (see also Brown, Spencer W.; McKenzie, Howard L.) (Box 67, Folder 9)
      - Nevers, Patricia, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 10)
      - New, Karen: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Nichols, Warren W., 1964 (Box 67, Folder 10)
      - Niederkorn, John A., Jr.: see Carson, L. H.
      - Nielsen, Michael, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 10)
      - Nikoro, Z. S.: see Dubinin, N. P.; Ginzburg, E.KH.
      - Nill, Annegreth: see Slatko, Barton E
      - Nissani, Moti, 1976 (Box 67, Folder 10)
      - Norrby, Erling: see Nichols, Warren W.
      - Nothel, Horst, 1987 (Box 67, Folder 11)
      - Novozhenov, Iu.I., 1971-1973 (with author's inscription) (Box 67, Folder 11)
      - Novy, Jill B.: see Kidwell, Margaret G.
      - Numbers, Ronald L., 1982 (Box 67, Folder 11)
      - Nur, Uzi, 1962-1963 (Box 67, Folder 12)
      - Nusslein-Volhard, Christiane: see Lohs-Schardin, Margit
      - Nuzhdin, N.I., 1946 (Box 67, Folder 13)
      - Oberwetter, James M.: see Boyd, A. E.
      - Obolenkova, Liudmila A.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Ohta, Kuniyoshi, 1981-1983 (with author's inscription) (Box 67, Folder 14)
      - Ohta, Tomoko, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 14)
      - Oleinikov, A.N., 1962 (with author's inscription) (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - Olenov, Iu.M., 1956 (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - Orlov, L.M., 1973 (with author's inscription) (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - Ordonez, M.: see Hoenigsberg, H.F.
      - Orlov, Leonid: see Malotkov, Georgii
      - Ornoy, A.: see Dudakov, E.
      - Osborne, R. H.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Osipov, D.V., 1975-1977 (see also Rautian, M.S.) (Box 67, Folder 16)
      - Osorio-Sanabria, G.: see Hoenigsberg, H.F.
      - Overton, Louise F.: see Sokoloff, Alexander
      - Ozeki, H.: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Paiusova, A. N.: see Altukhov, IU. P.
      - Pakhomov, A.A.: see Korochkin, L.I.
      - Palotie, Aarno: see Peltonen, Leena
      - Panelius, Samuel, 1967 (with author's inscription) (Box 67, Folder 17)
      - Panitz, Reinhard, 1965 (with author's inscription) (Box 67, Folder 17)
      - Panshin, I.B. "Geterokhromatinovaia schema operona i ee sledstviia" (typescript): see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Panshin, I.B. (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Pantin, C.F.A., undated (Box 67, Folder 17)
      - Pasteels, jean, 1938 (Box 67, Folder 17)
      - Pasteur, G.: see Volobuev, V.T.
      - Patau, K.: see Timofeev-Resovskii, Nikolai Vladimirovich
      - Patterson, J.T., 1932-1945 (Box 67, Folder 18)
      - Pavan, C.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Pavlovsky, Olga: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Pelisson, Alain: see Picard, Georges
      - Peltonen, Leena, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Pentzos-Daponte, Athena: see Sperlich, Diether
      - Periquet, G., 1979 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Perlman, M.: see Dudakov, E.
      - Perlovskii, Leonid I.. "Fizicheskie i metafizicheskie kontseptsii myshleniia" (typescript): see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Perlovskii (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Pernose, L. S.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Petit, Claudine, 1958-1968 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - Phadnis, H. S.: see Berg, Douglas E.
      - Picard, Georges, 1977-1978 (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Pijnacker, L.P.: see Koch, P
      - Pinsker, W., 1977-1978 (see also Sperlich, Diether) (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - Pipkin, Sarah Bedichek, 1942 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Pires, J. Murca: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Plus, Nadine: see David, Jean; Thomas-Orillard, Michele
      - Podlipaev, S.A.: see Osipov, D.V.
      - Polanco, de: see Hoenigsberg, H.F.
      - Polezhaev, L.V., 1946 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Poliakova, E.V., undated (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Poriadkova, N.A., 1956 (see also Timofeev-Resovskii, Nikolai Vladimirovich) (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - Postnikova, E. D.: see Dubinin, N. P.
      - Potter, Rensselaer, van, 1975 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - Poulson, Donald F.: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Poulson (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Prakash, Satya, 1967 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - Prasolova, N.V.: see Karakin, E.I.
      - Precsenyi, I., 1958-1959 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - Preston, Christine R.: see Engels, William R.
      - Priimagi, Andres F.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Prokof'eva-Belgovskaia, A.A., 1947-1978 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Provine, William B., undated (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Queal, M. L.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Quiot, J. M.: see Bouletreau, Michel
      - Radzhabli, S.I.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Raffel, Daniel: see Muller, H.J.
      - Raipulis, E.P., 1988 (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - Rauschenbach, I.Y.: see Korochkin, L.I.
      - Rautian, M.S., 1975 1978 (see also Osipov, D.V.) (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - Raymond, John D.: see Lim, J.K.
      - Rebay, Ilaria: see Fortini, Mark E.
      - Reed, T. Edward: see Sved, J.A.
      - Regel', E.D., 1964-1975 (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Renkawitz-Pohl, Renate, 1984 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - Reperan, Zh., 1980 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - Retherford, Robert D., undated (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - Revin, Iu.V.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Richards, O.W., 1955 (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - Richmond, Rollin C., 1970 (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - Rick, C.M.: see Mackinney, G.
      - Rodriguez, J.: see Hoenigsberg, H.F.
      - Rodriguez, Peter: see Dawson, S. P.
      - Rodwin, Viktor. Article: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Rodwin, Viktor (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Rohdendorf, Boris Borisovich, 1958 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - Rokitskii, P.F., 1964 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - Roll-Hnasen, Nils, 1984 (Box 68, Folder 12)
      - Romashov, D.D., 1925 1931 (Box 68, Folder 12)
      - Rose, Michael R., 1980 (Box 68, Folder 13)
      - Rossianov, Kirill O., 1993 (Box 68, Folder 13)
      - Roy, Subodh Kumar, 1958-1961 (with author's inscriptions) (Box 68, Folder 14)
      - Roychoudhury, Arun K.: see Nei, Masatoshi
      - Rubin, Gerald M.: see Bingham, Paul M.; Kidwell, Margaret G.
      - Ruddle, F.H.: see Lubs, H.A.
      - Ruffie, J.: see Boesiger, Ernest
      - Russell, E.S., 1955 (Box 68, Folder 15)
      - Rychkov, A. V.: see Balanovskaya, E. V.
      - Rychkov, IU. G.: see Balanovskaia, E. V.
      - Ryndich-Chistiakova, Alla Vladimirovna: see Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich
      - Saban, Rodger, 1984 (Box 68, Folder 15)
      - Sacha-Rov, V.V.: see Magrzhikovskaya, K.V.
      - Saedler, Heinz: see Nevers, Patricia
      - Sakharov, V.V., 1936-1946 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 16)
      - Salomian, L.S., 1971 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 17)
      - Sams, Joan: see Demerec, Milislav
      - Sander, Klaus: see Lohs-Schardin, Margit
      - Sapozhnikova, Frida. Articles (photocopies): see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Sapozhnikova (Box 17, Folders 3-4)
      - Sapp, Randall J.: see Stark, William S.
      - Sarto, Gloria E.: see Therman, Eeva
      - Sasakawa, Chihiro: see Berg, Douglas E.
      - Sato, Joyce E.: see Carson, Hampton L.
      - Savva, Savelii L.: see Zhukoborskii
      - Savvateeva, E.V.: see Korochkin, L.I.
      - Schaefer, Ruth E.: see Kidwell, Margaret G.
      - Schartl, Manfred: see Anders, Fritz
      - Schlessinger, David: Bowman, Lewis H.
      - Schmidt, Carl-Rudolf: see Anders, Fritz
      - Schmidt, Erwin R., 1978 (Box 68, Folder 17)
      - Schneider, David, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 17)
      - Scholl, A., undated (see also Anders, F.) (Box 68, Folder 18)
      - Schwab, M., 1973-1979 (see also Anders, F.) (Box 68, Folder 18)
      - Scudo, Francesco M., 1988-1990 (Box 68, Folder 19)
      - Sedov, Aleksandr Evgen'evich. Article: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Sedov (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Semenov, V.I.: see Maletskii, S.I.
      - Semenova, E.V.: see Maletskii, S.I.
      - Sewell, William H.: see Retherford, Robert D.
      - Shamakov, Sakhat: see Evgen'ev, Michael B.
      - Shandala, T.V., 1985-1986 (see also Gershenzon, S.M.) (Box 68, Folder 20)
      - Shapiro, N.I., 1945 (With author's inscription. See also see Ignat'ev, M.V.) (Box 68, Folder 20)
      - Sharat Chandra, H.: see Nur, Uzi
      - Shaskol'skii, D.V., 1988 (Box 68, Folder 20)
      - Shmal'gauzen, I.I., 1958 (Box 68, Folder 21)
      - Shmidt, V.M., 1972-1973 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 21)
      - Shockley, William, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 22)
      - Shprezeman, E.: see Timofeev-Resovskii, Nikolai Vladimirovich
      - Shtakel'berg, A.A., 1976 (Box 68, Folder 23)
      - Shturman, Dora Moiseevna. Article: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Shturman (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Shultz, Fred T.: see Lowry, Dorothy C.
      - Shvanevich, V.N., 1956 (with author's inscription) (Box 68, Folder 23)
      - Simmons, Michael J.: see Lim, J.K.
      - Simonelig, Martine: see Bucheton, Alain
      - Simonova, Olga B.: see Gerasimova, Tatiana I.
      - Skoblo, I.I.: see Osipov, D.V.; Rautian, M.S.
      - Skuratovskaia, Inessa Naumovna: see Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich
      - Slatko, Barton E., 1972-1979 (see also Green, M.M.) (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Smirnov, E.S., 1966 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Smorodintsev, A.A., 1970 (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Snyder, L.A.: see Lim, J.K.
      - Snyder, Sally H.: see Carson, Hampton L.
      - Sokoloff, Alexander, 1963-1967 (see also Dawson, Peter S.; Dobzhansky, Theodosius) (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Sokolov, N. N., 1937 (see also Dubinin, N. P.) (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Solomko, Aleksej Petrovich: see Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich
      - Sotina, N.: see Boldyreva, L.
      - Spassky, Boris: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Spassky, N.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Spencer, Warren P., 1940-1947 (Box 69, Folder 4)
      - Sperlich, Diether, 1967-1977 (see also Pinsker, W.) (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Spitsberg, Vitaly L., 1977 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Sprague, G.F., 1970 (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Stadler, L.J., undated (Box 69, Folder 7)
      - Stalker, Harrison D.: see Carson, Hampton L.
      - Stark, William S., 1992 (see also Griswold, M. Scott) (Box 69, Folder 7)
      - Starobogatov, Ia.I., 1968 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 7)
      - Stebbins, G. Ledyard, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 8)
      - Stewart, T. D.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Strokovskaia-Ponomarenko, Liudmila Ivanovna: see Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich
      - Stone, W.S.: see Patterson, J.T.
      - Strunnikov, V.A., 1969 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 8)
      - Sutugina, Liudmila Petrovna: see Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich
      - Svardson, Gunnar, 1943 (Box 69, Folder 8)
      - Sved, John A., 1963-1986 (see also Ayala, F. J.; Engels, William R.; Kidwell) (Box 69, Folder 9)
      - Svetlov, P.G., 1962-1972 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 10)
      - Sviridov, S.M.: see Karakin E.I.
      - Szyfman, L., 1981 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 11)
      - Tajima, Fumio: see Nei, Masatoshi
      - Takhtadzhian, A.L., 1957 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 12)
      - Tan, C.C. Article: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Tan (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Tandler, Bernard: see Ehrman, Lee
      - Tatsukawa, Kenichi: see Minamori, Sumio
      - Taylor, Milton W., 1980 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 12)
      - Tedesco, J.L.: see Cypher, J.J.
      - Telfer, J. D.: see Abrahamson, S.
      - Terent'ev, P.V., 1959-1969 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 13)
      - Therman, Eeva, 1980 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 13)
      - Thomas-Orillard, Michele, 1966-1982 (Box 69, Folder 14)
      - Thompson, James N., Jr., 1978 (see also Slatko, Barton E) (Box 69, Folder 15)
      - Thompson, Vinton, 1975-1987 (Box 69, Folder 15)
      - Throckmorton, L. H.: see Carson, Hampton L.
      - Timofeev-Resovskii, Nikolai Vladimirovich, 1934-1981 (with author's inscription) (Box 69, Folder 16)
      - Timofeeva, N.A.: see Titlianova, A.A.
      - Tiniakov, G. G.: see Dubinin, N. P.
      - Tinker, Harriet: see Dunn, L. C.
      - Titlianova, A.A., 1959-1962 (Box 69, Folder 17)
      - Tobari, Yoshiko N.: see Moriwaki, Daigoro
      - Todes, Daniel P., 1983 (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - Tracey, Martin L.: see Ayala, F. J.
      - Trass, H.H.: see Mazing, V.V.
      - Trusov, K.Z., 1949 (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - Trut, L.N.: see Beliaev, D.K.
      - Tsubota, Stuart I., 1991 (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - Trout, W.E.: see Kaplan, W.D.
      - Trut, L. N.: see Beliaev, D. K.
      - Truveller, K. A.: see Altukhov, IU. P.
      - Tsygvintsev, P.N.: see Kaidanov, Leonid Z.
      - Tupitsyna, E.M., 1967 (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - Turelli, Michael: see Kondrashov, Aleksei S.
      - Ulber, Margaret: see Therman, Eeva
      - Ulmasov, Khayot A.: see Evgen'ev, Michael B.
      - Ushakov, B.P., 1963-1964 (with author's inscription) (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Uschmann, Georg: see Hassenstein, Bernard
      - Valentine, James W.: see Ayala, F. J.
      - Varoczy, Edith: see Daniel, Lajos
      - Vaupel, James W., 1988 (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - Vaury, Chantal: see Bucheton, Alain
      - Vavilov, N.I., 1922 (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Veselkin, N.P.: see Reperan, Zh.
      - Vielkind, Ursula, 1976 (see also Kuhn, Claudia; Schwab, M.) (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Viktorova, G.V.: see Golubovskii, Mikhail
      - Voelker, Robert A., 1974 (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Vogt, R. C.: see Bull, James J.
      - Vol'kenshtein, M.V., 1984 (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Volobuev, V.T., 1989 2002 (with author's inscription) (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Voloshina, M.L.: see Golubovskii, Mikhail
      - Vorontsov, N.N., 1958-1987 (with author's inscription. See also Liapunova, E.A.; Timofeev-Resovskii, Nikolai Vladimirovich) (Box 70, Folder 5 to 10)
      - Vucinich, A., undated (Box 70, Folder 11)
      - Voskresenskaia, T. I.: see Alpatov, V. V.
      - Wallace, Bruce: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Wasserman, M.: see Carson, Hampton L.
      - Waters, Grady D.: see Khoury, Muin J.
      - Webb, G.C.: see v
      - Wedel, M.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Wei, Irene Y: see Carson, Hampton L.
      - Weiner, Douglas R., undated (Box 70, Folder 11)
      - Weisborn, Steven H., 1967 (Box 70, Folder 11)
      - Weisman, N.J.: see Maletskii, S.I.
      - Wen-Hsiung Li: see Frank, G.M.; Nei, Masatoshi
      - Weston-Hafer, Kathleen: see Berg, Douglas E.
      - Wheeler, Marshall R.: see Carson, Hampton L.
      - White, Michael J.D., 1973-1982 (Box 70, Folder 12)
      - Williams, George C, 1957 (Box 70, Folder 13)
      - Williamson, David L.: see Ehrman, Lee
      - Wills, C. J.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Winchester, A.M.: see Patterson, J.T.
      - Winge, Helga, 1965 (with author's inscription) (Box 70, Folder 13)
      - Wolf, P.M., undated (see also Gerlach, J.) (Box 70, Folder 13)
      - Woodruff, R.C., 1978 (with author's inscription. See also Slatko, Barton E.; Thompson, James N., Jr.) (Box 70, Folder 13)
      - Yadav, J.S.: see Liapunova, E.A.; see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Yanagisawa, Kaichiro: see Dunn, L. C.
      - Yen, J.H., 1971-1974 (Box 70, Folder 14)
      - Yoon, Sei Byung: see Fox, Allen S.
      - Young, Michael W., 1979-1981 (with author's inscription) (Box 70, Folder 14)
      - Zagoruiko, N.G.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Zakharov, I.K., 1984 1992 (with author's inscription. See also Golubovskii, Mikhail) (Box 70, Folder 15)
      - Zaki, Mokhamed A.: see Shmidt, V.M.
      - Zamorskii, A.D., 1940 (Box 70, Folder 16)
      - Zarapkin, 1943 1959 (with author's inscription) (Box 70, Folder 16)
      - Zaslavskii, V.A., 1966-1967 (with author's inscription) (Box 70, Folder 16)
      - Zavalishin, N.N.: see Ginzburg, E.KH.
      - Zherebtsova, Ella Nikolaevna: see Gershenzon, Sergei Mikhailovich
      - Zhimulev, I. F., 1977 (see also Dobzhansky, Theodosius) (Box 70, Folder 16)
      - Zholnerovskaia, E.I.: see Vorontsov, N.N.
      - Zhukoborskii, Savelii (aka Savva, Savelii L.). Works: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Zhukoborskii (Box 21, Folders 1-8)
      - Zimmering, S.: see Dobzhansky, Theodosius
      - Zumwalt, Gary S.: see Ayala, F. J.
      - Zunt, Joseph R.: see Lim, J.K.
    - Collections of works, 1926-1987 (Box 71, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Programs and publications of various conferences, 1962-2000 (Box 71, Folder 9 to 11)
    - Prose and poetry, journalism, publicistic works, and writings on general subjects see:
      - Delone, Vadim. Poetry (typescript with holograph corrections): see see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Delone, Vadim (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Fet, Viktor. "Behind the Iron Curtain" (photocopy of article): see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals-- Fet, Viktor (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Forest, Herman S. "From a window on Nevsky Prospekt": see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Forest (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Gliner, Erast: see Science and History of Science
      - Jensen, Ken. "Red star: Bogdanov builds a utopia": see see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Jensen (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Kagan, Viktor. "Vstrechi so stikhami i liud'mi": see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Kagan, V.K. (Box 8, Folders 2-3)
      - Khalif, Lev. "Lesorub, on prirodu liubit, ili V odnoi lodke, no po raznye storony barrikad": see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Khalif (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Leonovich, V.. Poetry (typescript): see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Arronet (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Makarenko, Mikhail., publication on him, and his writings and publications of 1983 (see his correspondence in Box 11, Folders 11-12)
        - "5-oe sentiabia: dokumental'nyi rasskaz" (typescript)
        - Autobiographical note
      - Malakhovskaia, Natalia. Poetry: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Malakhovskaia Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Petrochenkov, Valerii. Poetry (typescript and photocopies): see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Petrochenkov Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Reznik, Semen. Articles: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Reznik (Box 16, Folders 5-9)
      - Vin'kovetskaia, Diana. Essays: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Vin'kovetskaia (Box 19, Folder 7-8)
      - Vin'kovetskii, Iakov: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Vin'kovetskii (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Subseries VI.2: Printed Materials, 1937-2004
    Contains books and brochures, magazines, newspapers and clippings. Oversize materials stored in Flat boxes #1-3.
    - Books and brouchures, undated, 1956-1972 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Magazines, 1971-1999 (Box 72, Folder 2 to 9)
    - Newspapers and clippings, 1937-2004 (Soviet, Russian émigré, French, and German newspapers and clippings on various subjects) (Box 1-3)
  - Subseries VI.3: Various research and reference materials, 1939-2004
    Publications on various scholars by various authors; articles of various authors on retinoblastoma; and records of "Soveshchanie po genetike i selektsii pri redaktsii zhurnala 'Pod znamenem marksizma'" of 1939.
    - Publications on various scholars, 1950s-2004 (Box 72, Folder 10 to 12)
    - Retinoblastoma (articles of various authors on the subject) (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Soveshchanie po genetike i selektsii pri redaktsii zhurnala "Pod znamenem marksizma", 1939 (Box 73, Folder 1 to 10)
    - Varia (Box 73, Folder 11 to 13)